Hi!
I'm back with my expert Anne, who is a reflexologist, and I'm just about to begin soaking my feet in this bowl of hot water.
Anne, what can we expect when we come to reflexologist?
Typically, what happens?
Well, if you go to a spa for reflexology massage it's a little bit different than going into a room and laying on a table and getting a full shiatsu or Swedish massage.
You'll be normally fully clothed because you're just dealing with the feet and the hands and the lower legs.
You'll be normally sitting up right.
It's kind of a great way to learn about massage because you're facing the massage therapist, so you're able to actually talk to them about what specific pressure points do and where the pressure points are related in your body, so you're able to get a much clearer idea specifically step by step what massage can offer you.
How long does it take?
Normally, a full reflexology treatment takes between half an hour and an hour.
Working on reflexology for more than an hour is usually a bit too much for your lymphatic and your circulatory systems.
There will normally be a soak to soften your feet and to sort of get the blood flowing first, and then feet will be cleaned and scrubbed, and then they'll be dried off and we'll go to work on your feet.
Because there's no gliding or sliding along larger muscles, reflexology doesn't require any lotion or oils.
It's a nice, quick, sort of more convenient massage.